Diego DORN

Research Engineer

 Diego works on the mitigation of **systemic risks** from **general-purpose artificial intelligence** systems.

He has extensive expertise in **software engineering** and experience in **teaching**, **leadership** and **communication** from his volunteering. He finishes his master in Communication Systems in August 2024.

Work Experience

Paris Research engineer at CeSIA (French Center for AI safety)

Feb. 2024 – present Lead the design of benchmarks to evaluate monitoring systems of LLM agents.

Published "BELLS: A Framework Towards Future Proof Benchmarks for the Evaluation of LLM Safeguards" in the NextGen AI Safety workshop at ICML 2024.

Safeguards" in the NextGen Al Safety workshop at ICML 2024.

Across Europe Head Teacher for three ML4Good, a summer school on systemic AI risk (ml4good.org)

Aug. 2023 – present Delivery and improvement of 10 days of technical and conceptual content for ~20 participants, covering

threat modeling, technical safety and AI policy.

Cambridge Research assistant, Machine Learning Group, Cambridge University

July - Sep. 2023 Research on goal misgeneralisation in Reinforcement Learning (RL) with N. Alex and D. Krueger. Published

"Goal Misgeneralization as Implicit Goal Conditioning" in the GCRL workshop at Neurips 2023

Lausanne Lead developer for the startup SPRIG (sprigproofs.org)

Jan. 22 – May 23 Developing a distributed platform to increase confidence in mathematical proofs.

EDUCATION

Lausanne Master's in Communication Systems, Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)

Sep. 2021 – present Focus on artificial intelligence, formal verification and advanced algorithms. Minor in Mathematics.

Interlaken

★ Summer school "Science and Policy – How to bridge the gap?"

July 2023 5 days on science for policy, science communication, open science and the Swiss policy landscape.

London ARENA, Alignment Research Engineer Accelerator (arena.education)

May – June 2023 6 weeks intensive training on interpretability, RL and training at scale.

Lausanne Bachelor's in Mathematics at EPFL

Sep. 18 – July 2021 Passed with a 5.42/6 average and top 5/100 of my year.

Volunteering

Lausanne Founder and President of the Safe AI Lausanne student association

Sep. 22 – March 24 Led a team of 8 through the design of a strategy, resulting in a 10-day winter school on systemic AI risks, 3

talks and 2 panel discussions with a total of 10 experts, and a talk for TEDxEcublens.

Lausanne President of COFD, the mathematics students' association of EPFL

Sep. 20 – Sep. 21 Management of a team of 14 people, dialogue with the direction of the faculty.

Many places National organisation committee of the french tournament of young mathematicians, TFJM²

Sep. 20 – May 21 Coordination of 9 events for 600 participants, communication, and creation of a new online infrastructure.

Awards & Extra

Bruxelles 1st place in the hackathon the "Digital Services Act RAG Race"

February 2024 Creation of a Q&A system for questions on the DSA based on open-source models, in a team of 3, during a

7 hours hackathon organised by the PEReN and the European Commission.

Earth **Game development, tool design, websites** (cozyfractal.com/showcase)

2014 – present Creation of 10+ small games under strong time constraints and pressure for game jams, a 2D EsoLang

(Asciidots), multiple software tools and websites. Teamwork and sprints.

HARD SKILLS

Python (pytorch, huggingface, streamlit, click, mypy, pytest...) . 6000h • Traini

JavaScript / CSS / HTML (VueJS, TailwindCSS) 500h

Rust, C++, Scala, LaTeX 300h each

System Administration (Git, Docker, Bash, remote machines...) 200h •

• Training in Non-Violent Communication

· Public speaking

SOFT SKILLS

• Native in French (C2)

• Fluent in English (C1)